In this video, we're going to take a rest a little bit and talk about how compilers
在这段视频中，我们将稍微看看睡觉，然后谈谈编译器是如何
handle errors and in particular, what kind of error handling functionality is
处理错误，特别是什么类型的错误处理功能
available in parsers. Compiler has two relatively distinct jobs. The first is to
在解析器中可用。编译器有两个相对不同的工作。第一个是
translate valid programs. That is if it gets a program from a programmer that is
翻译有效的程序。也就是说，如果它从程序员那里获得程序，即
correct, is a valid program, it needs to produce correct code for that program.
正确，是一个有效的程序，它需要为该程序生成正确的代码。
Now, distinct from that task is the job of giving good feedback. For erroneous
现在，与这项任务不同的是提供良好反馈的工作。对于错误的
program and even just detecting the invalid programs we don't want to compile
程序，甚至只检测我们不想编译的无效程序
any program that isn't a valid program in the programming language. And programming
在编程语言中不是有效程序的任何程序。和编程
languages have many different kinds of errors. Here's just a few. So for example,
语言有许多不同类型的错误。这里只有几个。举个例子，
we might have lexical errors, that's for using characters that don't even appear in
我们可能会有词汇错误，这是因为我们使用的字符甚至没有出现在
any balanced symbol in the language and these would be detected by lexical
语言中的任何平衡符号都会被词法检测到
analysis phase. We could have syntax errors and this would be the parsing
分析阶段。我们可能会有语法错误，这就是解析
errors when all the individual lexical units are correct but they're assembled in
当所有单独的词汇单元都是正确的，但它们被组合在
some way that doesn't make sense and we don't know how to compile it. There could
这在某种程度上说不通，而且我们不知道如何编译它。可能会有
be semantic errors for example when types mismatch. Here I've declared excess in
是语义错误，例如，当类型不匹配时。在这里我已经声明了超额
integer and use it as a function and that would be the job of type checker to catch
整数，并将其用作函数，这将是类型检查器要捕获的工作
those. And then Actually, there may be many errors in your program that are not
那些。实际上，您的程序中可能会有许多不是这样的错误
errors of the programming language. The program you wrote is actually a valid
编程语言错误。您编写的程序实际上是有效的
program but it doesn't do what you intended. You're likely bugging your
程序，但它没有执行您想要的操作。你很可能在窃听你的
program and so while the compiler can detect many kinds of errors, it doesn't
程序，因此尽管编译器可以检测到许多类型的错误，但它不能
detect all of them and, you know once we get past what the compiler can do, then
检测所有它们，您知道，一旦我们了解了编译器所能做的事情，那么
it's up to testers and users to find the rest of the problems in the program. So,
这是由测试人员和用户来找到程序中问题的睡觉。所以,
what are the requirements for a good error handling? Well, we want the [inaudible]
良好的错误处理有哪些要求？嗯，我们想要[听不见的]
report errors accurately and clearly so that we can identify what the problem is
准确而清晰地报告错误，以便我们可以确定问题所在
quickly and fix it. The compiler itself should recover from the error, error
快点把它修好。编译器本身应该从错误、错误
quickly. So when it hits an error, it shouldn' t take a long time to make a
快点。因此，当它遇到错误时，应该不会花很长时间。
[inaudible] on what to do before proceeding. And finally, we don't want
[听不见]在继续之前要做什么。最后，我们不希望
error handling to slow down the compilation of valid code. That is, we
用于减慢有效代码编译速度的错误处理。就是我们
shouldn't pay a price for the error handling if we're not really using it. I'm
如果我们不是真的在使用错误处理，就不应该为它付出代价。我
going to talk about three different kinds of error handling. Panic mode and error
我们将讨论三种不同类型的错误处理。死机模式和错误
productions are the two that are used in current compiler. So these are actually
产生式是当前编译器中使用的两种。所以这些实际上是
things that people use today. Automatic local or global correction is an idea that
今天人们使用的东西。自动局部或全局校正是一种
was pursued excessively in the past. And I think it's historically quite interesting
在过去被过分追求。我认为这在历史上是很有趣的
particularly as a contrast what people do today and also why people try to do it a
特别是作为对比，今天的人们做什么，也是为什么人们试图这样做的原因
long ago. [inaudible] is the simplest and most popular method of error recovery
很久以前了。[听不见]是最简单、最流行的错误恢复方法
that's widely used and the basic ideas that when an error is detected, the parser
它被广泛使用，其基本思想是当检测到错误时，解析器
is going to begin discarding tokens until one that has a clear role in the language
将开始丢弃令牌，直到一个在语言中具有明确角色的令牌
is found and that's going to try to restart itself and continue from that
将尝试重新启动并从该位置继续
point on. And these tokens, the ones that it's looking for are called the
指向。而这些令牌，它正在寻找的那些被称为
Synchronizing Tokens. And these are just tokens that have a well-known role in the
正在同步令牌。这些只是一些令人熟知的代币，在
language and so that we can reliably identify where we are. So, a typical
这样我们就可以可靠地识别我们所在的位置。所以，一个典型的
strategy might be to try to skip to the end of a statement or to the end of a
策略可能是尝试跳到语句末尾或
function if an error is found in a statement or function and then begin
函数(如果在语句或函数中发现错误)，然后开始
parsing either the next statement or the next function. So let's look at a simple
解析下一条语句或下一函数。那么让我们来看一个简单的
hypothetical example of panic mode error recovery. So here's an expression. Clearly
假设的死机模式错误恢复示例。这是一个表达式。很明显
it has a problem. We shouldn't have two plus signs in a row so something has gone
它有一个问题。我们不应该连续有两个加号，所以出了点问题
wrong here at the second plus and what's going to happen is the parser is going to
第二个加号出错，接下来会发生的是解析器将
come along. The parser is going to be proceeding from left to right. It's gonna
跟我来。解析器将从左向右前进。它将会是
see the open-paren, it's gonna see the number one, it's gonna see the plus
看开场-帕伦，它会看到第一名，它会看到加号
everything is good and then it's gonna see the second plus and it's not gonna know
一切都很好，然后它会看到第二个加号，它不会知道
what to do. It's going to realize. That it's stuck and that there's no expression
该怎么做。它会意识到。它卡住了，没有表情
in the language that has two p lus signs in a row and it needs to do something to
在具有连续两个手势的语言中，它需要做些什么来
recover. It's encountered a parsing error and it has to take some error action at
恢复健康。它遇到了解析错误，它必须在以下位置采取一些错误操作
this point. So in panic mode recovery, what it's going to do is it's going to hit
这一点。所以在恐慌模式恢复中，它要做的是
the panic button. So right at this point, it's going to say I give up, I'm not
紧急按钮。所以在这一点上，我会说我放弃了，我不会
parsing normally anymore. It goes into a different mode. Where is simply throwing
不再正常解析。它会进入不同的模式。在哪里简单地扔
away input until it finds something that it recognizes and for example, we could
离开输入，直到它找到它能识别的东西，例如，我们可以
say that the policy in this particular, for this particular kind of error, is to
假设在这种特殊情况下，对于这种特殊的错误，政策是
skip ahead to the next integer and then try to continue. So, we'll just throw away
向前跳到下一个整数，然后尝试继续。所以，我们就把它扔掉
the plus in this case and then it would restart here at the two, expecting to see
在这种情况下的加号，然后它会在这两个点重新开始，期望看到
another integer. Try to finish off this expression and it would treat that as one
另一个整数。尝试结束此表达式，它会将其视为
+ two and then the parenthesis would match and the rest of the expression would parse
+2，然后圆括号将匹配，表达式的睡觉将被解析
just fine. Now in tools such Bison, which is widely used parser generator and one
挺好的。现在在诸如Bison这样的工具中，这是一个被广泛使用的解析器生成器
that you may use for the project, there is a special terminal symbol called error to
，有一个特殊的端子符号，称为ERROR TO
describe how much input to skip and the productions that are given in Bison look
描述要跳过多少输入以及在Bison Look中给出的产品
like this. So you would say at the possibilities for e are that e could be an
像这样。所以你会说e的可能性是，e可能是一个
integer, e could be an. The sum of the two e's, two expressions, it could be a
整数，e可以是一个。两个e的和，两个表达式，它可能是一个
parenthesized expression or if none of this work, okay. So these are the normal
带括号的表达式，或者如果这些都不起作用，好的。所以这些都是正常的
productions. Alright, If none of those work, then we could try some of these
制作。好吧，如果这些都不管用，那么我们可以试试这些
productions that have error in them. And error is a special symbol for Bison and it
其中有错误的制作。错误是野牛和它的特殊象征
says, well, these are the alternatives to try if these things over here didn't work.
他说，如果这里的这些东西不起作用，这些都是可以尝试的选择。
So, if you find an error. Let's focus on this one right here so if this says that
所以，如果你发现一个错误。我们把重点放在这里，所以如果这上面写着
if you find an error while you're trying to parse an e. Okay, we haven't actually
如果您在尝试解析e时发现错误。好的，我们实际上还没有
said how that works yet. We'll see that in the future videos but conceptually, the
已经说过这是怎么回事了。我们将在未来的视频中看到这一点，但从概念上讲，
parser is trying to recognize one of these kinds of expressions here. It's in a state
解析器正在尝试识别其中一种表达式。它处于一种状态
where it thinks it wanted to see an integer or a + or a parenthesized
其中，它认为希望看到整数、+或圆括号
expression and if that isn't working out i f it get stuck well then hit the panic
表达，如果这不起作用，如果它被很好地卡住了，那么就惊慌失措
button and you can declare that it's in error state and it can throw away all the
按钮，您可以声明它处于错误状态，并且它可以丢弃所有
input. This error will match all the input up to the next integer. And then this
输入。此错误将匹配直到下一个整数的所有输入。然后是这个
whole thing could be counted as an e. As one of these things and then we will try
整件事都可以算作e。作为其中的一件事，然后我们会试一试
to continue the parsing. Similarly, if we encounter an error somewhere inside a pair
以继续解析。类似地，如果我们在一对中的某处遇到错误
of match parenthesis, well, we could just throw away the whole thing and just reset
我们可以把整件事扔掉，然后重置
at the parenthesis boundaries and they continue parsing. So these are two
在括号边界处，它们继续解析。所以这是两个
possible error recovery strategies if we find an error for this particular kind of
如果我们发现这种特定类型的错误，可能的错误恢复策略
symbol in the grammar. And you can have these error, These productions that
语法中的符号。你可以有这些错误，这些作品
involved the error token for, for as many different kinds of symbols in the language
涉及语言中任意多个不同类型的符号的错误标记
as you like. Another common strategy is to use what are known as error productions
随你便。另一种常见的策略是使用所谓的错误产生
and this specify known common mistakes that programmers make adjust as
这指定了已知的常见错误，程序员会根据这些错误进行调整
alternative productions in the grammar. So here's a simple example, let's say we were
语法中的替代产生式。这里有一个简单的例子，让我们假设我们是
working on a programming language or compiler for a programming language that
使用编程语言或用于编程语言的编译器，该编程语言
was used by a lot of mathematicians and instead of writing Five x like computer
被许多数学家使用，而不是像计算机一样写5x
scientists do, these guys always wanted to write five x to just juxtapose the five
科学家是这样做的，这些家伙总是想写五个x来把五个并列在一起。
and the x to look more like normal mathematical notation. And they complain
而x看起来更像是普通的数学符号。他们抱怨说
that this is always giving them parser errors. If the parser is just complaining
这总是会给他们带来解析器错误。如果解析器只是在抱怨
over and over again then this is not a well formed expression. Well, we could
一遍又一遍，这不是一个很好的表达。嗯，我们可以
just go in to our grammar and add a production that made of, of well form. We
只需进入我们的语法，添加一个由，形式良好的产品组成的产品。我们
could just say well now it's legal, if I have that one kind of expression is just
我只能说，现在这是合法的，如果我有一种表达方式，那就是
to have two expressions that [inaudible] opposed next to each other with no
有两个[听不见的]紧挨着的表达，没有
intervening operator. And this, has a disadvantage obviously of complicating the
介入操作员。而这显然有一个不利之处，那就是使
grammar. If we do this a lot our grammar is gonna get a lot harder to understand.
语法。如果我们这样做太多，我们的语法会变得更难理解。
It's gonna be a lot harder to maintain and essentially all this is doing is promoting
它将更难维护，基本上所有这些都是在推广
common mistakes to alternative syntax but this is used in practice. Peo ple do this
常见的错误，以替代语法，但这是在实践中使用。请大家这样做
sort of thing and you will see for example when you use TCC and other production C
例如，当您使用TCC和其他产品C++时，您将会看到
compilers they will often warn you about things you're not supposed to do but
编译器他们会经常警告你一些你不应该做的事情，但是
they'll accept them anyway and this is essentially the mechanism by which they do
他们无论如何都会接受的，这基本上就是他们这样做的机制
that. Last strategy I want to talk about a little bit is error correction. So, so far
那。最后，我想谈一谈纠错策略。那么到目前为止
we've just talked about strategies for detecting errors but we could also try to
我们刚刚讨论了检测错误的策略，但是我们也可以尝试
fix errors that is if the program has mistakes in it, the compiler could try to
修复错误，即如果程序中有错误，编译器可以尝试
help the program out and say oh, you obviously didn't mean to write that. Let
帮助程序，然后说，哦，你显然不是故意要写的。让我们
me try to find a program for you that, that works. And, these kind of corrections
我试着为你找一个能行得通的程序。而且这种修正，
in some sense we wanted to find programs that are nearby, programs that aren't too
从某种意义上说，我们希望找到附近的程序，不太靠近的程序
different from the programs at the, that the programmer supplied but we couldn't
与程序员提供但我们不能提供的程序不同
compile correctly. And there's a few different things that you can do to the
正确编译。这里有几个不同的事情，你可以对
things that people have tried are things like token insertions and deletions. So
人们尝试过的东西是像插入和删除令牌这样的东西。所以
here you'd like to minimize the edit distance. That would be the metric that
在这里，您希望最小化编辑距离。这就是衡量标准，
you would use to determine whether a program was close to the original program,
您将使用来确定程序是否接近原始程序，
that the programmer supplied. You could also do exhaustive search within some
程序员提供的。您还可以在一些
bounce to try all possible programs that are close to the program that was
弹出以尝试所有可能的程序，这些程序与之前
supplied. And, a couple of disadvantages to this actually, number of disadvantages.
供应的。实际上，这有几个缺点，有几个缺点。
You can imagine that this is hard to implement. It, it's actually quite
你可以想象这是很难实现的。它，它其实挺
complex. This will slow down the parsing of correct programs because we need to
很复杂。这将减慢正确程序的解析速度，因为我们需要
keep enough state around that we can manage the search or, or the editing in
保持足够的状态，以便我们可以在中管理搜索或/或编辑
the case of that way actually doing counter and error and of course nearby is
这种方式实际执行计数器和错误的情况，当然是附近的情况是
not really, is not really that clear what that means and various notions of nearby
不是真的，不是很清楚那是什么意思，以及附近的各种概念
may or may not actually take us to a program of the, the programmer would
可能会也可能不会真正带我们去看一个程序，程序员会
actually be happy with. The best one example of error correction is the
实际上很高兴和你在一起。纠错的最佳示例之一是
compiler PL [crosstalk]. This is PL [inaudible] compiler, that's the PL part
编译器PL[串扰]。这是PL[听不见]编译器，那是PL部分
and the C stands for either correction or Cornell which is where the compiler was
C代表更正或Cornell，这就是编译器所在的位置
built and PL [crosstalk] is well-known for being willing to compile absolutely
Build and PL[相声]以愿意绝对编译而闻名
anything. You could, you could give it the phone book. You can and people did give it
什么都行。你可以，你可以把电话簿给它。你可以而且人们确实给了它
things like speech from Hamlet soliloquy and it would print out a lot of error
就像哈姆雷特的独白一样，它会打印出很多错误
messages. Sometimes, these error messages would be very funny to read. And it would,
留言。有时，阅读这些错误消息会非常有趣。它将会，
in the end, do correction and produce always a valid running PL [inaudible]
最后，进行校正并始终产生有效的运行PL[听不见]
program. And you might ask why do people bother with that? It doesn't seem but that
程序。你可能会问，人们为什么要为这个烦恼呢？看起来不像，但是
may not seem very compelling To us today. And have to realize that when this work
今天对我们来说可能不是很有说服力。并且必须意识到，当这项工作奏效时
was done back in the 1970s people live in a very different world. There was a very
是在20世纪70年代完成的，人们生活在一个非常不同的世界里。有一个非常大的
slow recompilation cycle. It could take a whole day To get your program To compile
重新编译周期较慢。编译您的程序可能需要一整天的时间
and run, you would essentially submit your program in the morning and you might not
然后运行，你基本上会在早上提交你的程序，而你可能不会
get results back until the afternoon. And, with that kind of turnaround cycle, Even
下午之前把结果拿回来。而且，有了这样的周转周期，即使
one syntax error in your program was devastating. You can lose a whole day
程序中的一个语法错误是毁灭性的。你可能会损失一整天
because you mistype the keyword and having the compiler try to take a stab at finding
因为您输入了错误的关键字，并让编译器尝试查找
a working program for you if the correction was small and you save an
如果校正很小，并且您保存了一个工作程序，则会为您提供一个工作程序
entire day, you know to think it can fix that one small mistake you made and give
一整天，你都知道它可以弥补你犯下的一个小错误
you a valid run, that was actually a useful thing to do. And so the goal then
你跑得很好，这实际上是一件很有用的事情.所以我们的目标是
was to find as many errors in one cycle as possible. They would try, they would try
就是在一个周期内找出尽可能多的错误。他们会试着，他们会试着
to find as many errors to try to recover. Find as many errors as possible. Give you
查找尽可能多的错误以尝试恢复。找出尽可能多的错误。给你
as good feedback as possible so you could fix as many errors, avoid as many retry
尽可能好的反馈，以便您可以修复尽可能多的错误，避免尽可能多的重试
cycles as possible. And, and even possibly automatically correct the program. So that
尽可能的循环。甚至有可能自动修正程序。所以
you could see if the correction were right and, and then possibly the, the results
你可以看到修正是否正确，然后可能会看到结果。
you got back were useful on the [inaudible] to do even more debugging
你回来后对[听不见的]做更多的调试很有用
before the next round. Now today, we're in a completely different situation. We were
在下一轮之前。今天，我们处于一个完全不同的情况。我们是在
very fast, almost interactive recompilation cycle for many projects and
许多项目的重新编译周期非常快，几乎是交互式的
as a result, users generally aren't interested in finding many errors. They
因此，用户通常对查找许多错误不感兴趣。他们
ten d to correct only one error per cycle. Compilers still report many errors, I'll
10d以在每个周期内仅纠正一个错误。编译器仍然报告许多错误，我将
give you lots and lots of errors but my observation certainly might have it.
给你带来了很多错误，但我的观察肯定是有错的。
Personally, what I see many other people do is they only fix the first one because
就我个人而言，我看到很多其他人只修好第一个，因为
it's the most reliable and the one that definitely needs to be fixed before,
这是最可靠的，也是肯定需要修复的，
before you can try to compile again. If the compilation is fast enough, that's
然后才能再次尝试编译。如果编译速度足够快，那就是
probably the most proactive thing to do. And as result, complex error recovery
可能是最积极主动的做法。因此，复杂的错误恢复
today is just less compelling than it was a few decades ago.
与几十年前相比，今天的情况没有那么令人信服。